Guide to the Mary Morrison papers, 1954-2006.
Morrison, Mary papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Mary Morrison papers, 1954-2006.
29-2-4077
Morrison, Mary
3 Cubic Feet.
Correspondence, publications, reports.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, publications, reports and subject files realted to Morrison's work as a professor in the Division of Nutritional Sciences (1960-1988) and with the Nutrition Education Program in East Harlem, the University Animal Welfare Committee (UAWC) and faculty retirement issues.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor emeritus in the Division of Nutritional Sciences, Cornell University.
Morrison served in the Royal Canadian Air Force from 1943-1946 and received a B.A. form the University of Alberta, a master's degree in food and nutrition from Washington State University, and a PhD in biochemistry/nutrition from the University of Wisconsin.
Morrison taught from 1960-1988 and her teaching and research focused on protein and amino acid nutrition. At Cornell she developed an undergraduate honors seminar, directed a multidisciplinary research action program in East Harlem, New York (1969-1976) and chaired the Northeast Regional Technical Committee, which coordinated the research work of faculty in ten universities.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, publications, reports and subject files realted to Morrison's work as a professor in the Division of Nutritional Sciences (1960-1988) and with the Nutrition Education Program in East Harlem, the University Animal Welfare Committee (UAWC) and faculty retirement issues.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Morrison, Mary; Cornell University -- Faculty.; Cornell University. Graduate School of Nutrition.; Cornell University. East Harlem Project.
Subjects:
Nutrition -- Study and teaching -- United States.; Expanded Food and Nutrition Education Program.; Animal welfare.; College teachers -- New York (State) -- Retirement.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Biographical, 1961-2994 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Publications - by Morrison, 1954-1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Teaching Lab, 1970-1979 (Box 1, Folder 2a)
- Morrison Research, 1960-1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- High School Science Program, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- New York State Nutrition Institute, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Students advised by Morrison, 1963-1983 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Rsearch - Doyle Pharmaceutical Company, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Correspondence, 1960-1999 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Correspondence - on campus, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Nutrition Education Program - Grad Student Participation, 1970-1979 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Nutrition Clinic Study, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Summary of Trip to East Harlem, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Nutrition Education Program - East Harlem, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Nutrition Education Program - East Harlem, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Nutition Education Program - East Harlem, January-October 1971 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Nutrition Education Program - East Harlem, November-December 1971 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Nutrition Education Program - East Harlem, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Nutrition Education Program - East Harlem, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- University Animal Welfare Committee, 1970-1979 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- University Animal Welfare Committee - Articles, 1970-1989 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- University Animal Welfare Committee - Protocols - Compliance Forms, 1980-1989 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- University Animal Welfare Committee, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- University Animal Welfare Committee, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- University Animal Welfare Committee, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- University Animal Welfare Committee, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- University Animal Welfare Committee, January-August 1985 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- University Animal Welfare Committee, September-November 1985 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- University Animal Welfare Committee, December 1985-1986 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- University Animal Welfare Committee, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- University Animal Welfare Committee - Working Papers, 1978-1987 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- DNS Animal Committee, 1970-1979 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- DNS Animal Committee, 1980-1983 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- DNS Animal Committee, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- DNS Animal Committee, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- DNS Animal Committee, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Animal Use- Orientation, Ethics and Regulations, 1980-1989 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- DNS Animal Facilities - Inspection Reports, Correspondence, 1980-1989 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Animal Use Guides (Box 2)
- Association of Cornell University Emeritus Professors - Charters, 1980-1999 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- University Faculty Retirement/Emeritus Issues - correspondence, memos, publications, 1966-1982 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- University Faculty Retirement/Emeritus Issues - correspondence, memos, publications, 19983-19984 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- University Faculty Retirement/Emeritus Issues - correspondence, memos, publications, 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- University Faculty Retirement/Emeritus Issues - correspondence, memos, publications, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- University Faculty Retirement/Emeritus Issues - correspondence, memos, publications, January-July 1988 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- University Faculty Retirement/Emeritus Issues - correspondence, memos, publications, August-December 1988 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- University Faculty Retirement/Emeritus Issues - correspondence, memos, publications, January-May 1989 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- University Faculty Retirement/Emeritus Issues - correspondence, memos, publications, June-December 1989 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- University Faculty Retirement/Emeritus Issues - correspondence, memos, publications, January-March 1990 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- University Faculty Retirement/Emeritus Issues - correspondence, memos, publications, April-December 1990 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- University Faculty Retirement/Emeritus Issues - correspondence, memos, publications, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- University Faculty Retirement/Emeritus Issues - correspondence, memos, publications, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- University Faculty Retirement/Emeritus Issues - correspondence, memos, publications, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- University Faculty Retirement/Emeritus Issues - correspondence, memos, publications, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- University Faculty Retirement/Emeritus Issues - correspondence, memos, publications, 1996 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- University Faculty Retirement/Emeritus Issues - correspondence, memos, publications, January-June 1997 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- University Faculty Retirement/Emeritus Issues - correspondence, memos, publications, July-October 1997 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- University Faculty Retirement/Emeritus Issues - correspondence, memos, publications, November-December 1997 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- University Faculty Retirement/Emeritus Issues - correspondence, memos, publications, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- University Faculty Retirement/Emeritus Issues - correspondence, memos, publications, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- University Faculty Retirement/Emeritus Issues - correspondence, memos, publications, 2000-2006 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Faculty Retirement Data, 1982-1997 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Retirement Material, no dates (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Retiree Survey, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Retirement Planning, 1999-2000 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- ACEUP - Stationery (Box 3, Folder 6)
- "Connecting" Association of Cornell University Emeritus Professors Newsletter, 1995-2006 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Kendal Community Committee, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Honors Students - Bios, 1975-1985 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Honors Students, 1962-1987 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Honors Committee, 1960-1983 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Honors Committee, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Honors Committee, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Honors Committee, 1986-1991 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Eastern Colleges Science Conference, 1983-1984 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- DNS Fellowships, 1990-1999 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Faculty Council, 1982-1987 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Faculty Council, 1988-1993 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- College Voting Committee, 1990-1999 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Stephen Weiss Presidential Fellows - Establishment, 1992-1996 (Box 3, Folder 20)